So now we're ready to build the Web index. We're going to use the split operation to do this.
准备好了吧 使用分解操作来完成构建网络索引
So we can certainly build a way to separate all the words
没错 我们自己就可以构建一个方法
in a Web page ourselves using the operation we've already seen.
对网页上出现的词进行分解 通过刚刚的操作可知
We can use indexing to go through the letters in the string
可利用索引来浏览字符串中的字符
We can identify characters that we think of as separating words such as a space or a comma.
用作区分的词是可以识别的 比如空格或逗号
And we can collect those all as separate strings.
可全部作为单独字符串采集
The good news is Python provides a built-in operation that does exactly what we need.
好消息是 Python 提供了内置操作 可精准达成我们的需求
It's called split. We invoke split on a string
该操作称为 split 即分解 我们在字符串中调入 split
and what it outputs is a list of the words in the string.
输出内容则是字符串中的单词列表
For now we're not going to worry too much about the details of how split decides how to separate a string into words,
暂时 我们不用太操心 split 具体如何分解字符串成词
but let's look at a few examples to see that it does something pretty close to what we want for building our Web index.
但不妨通过几个例子来了解 它与构建网络索引很类似
So we've defined quote as a string which is this quote from Robert Reich.
这里 我们定义为字符串的引用来自罗伯特•赖克 (Robert Reich)
"In Washington it's dog eat dog. In academia, it's exactly the opposite."
"In Washington it's dog eat dog. In academia, it's exactly the opposite."
And now we'll use split to divide the quote into its words.
现在 要使用 split 来将引用分解成词
And you can see the result.
我们来看看结果
We have a list where the elements of the list are the words from the quote.
出现一个列表 构成元素正是引用里出现的词
And split does a pretty good job of dividing the string into the words that we want for our Web index.
这里 split 很好地将字符串分解成了构建网页索引所需的词
It's not perfect. We can see that Washington, which was followed by a comma in the quote,
但并不完美 比如在引用中 Washington 一词后面多了个逗号
ends up as the string Washington including the comma.
结果就是 字符串中的 Washington 后面也有逗号
That's a different value than the keyword Washington.
这么一来 这个值就不是关键词 Washington 而是另一个不同的值了
So if we search for Washington and we built our index this way, we're not going to actually find this occurance.
尽管我们想要搜索 Washington 也这么构建了索引 但在搜索结果中 它并不会出现
So this isn't perfect, but it's going to be good enough for what we use for now.
尽管仍不完美 但足够现阶段使用了
Later on we can think about ways to divide the Web page into its component words
稍后 我们可以思索如何分解网页成词
in a way that will be more accurate.
并使结果更加精确
Figuring out exactly how to decide when something's a new word is a fairly tough problem, though.
当然 要确定出现新词时如何操作 确实是比较困难的
As a second example to get a feel for how split works, let's try another quote.
我们来看第二个例子 了解如何执行 split 先看下另一个引用
Here we have a quote from David Letterman.
下面这句话引自大卫·莱特曼 (David Letterman)
"There's no business like show business, but there are several businesses like accounting."
"There's no business like show business, but there are several businesses like accounting."
I've introduced a new Python constrict. We're using the triple quote here.
之前我介绍过 Python 结构 这里就要用到三重引号了
The nice thing about triple quotes is that we can divide them over multiple lines.
三重引号的好处是 可以将之分成多行
When we tried to enter the previous quote using just the double quotes, it fell off the edge of the screen.
之前只使用双引号输入引用时 会溢出屏幕边缘
Using triple quotes, we can define one string spread over multiple lines.
而使用三重引号 则可以将一个字符串定义到多行
And now when we print out the result of splitting the quote, we see it's divided into words.
现在 打印分解引用的结果时 可以看到 引用成功地分解成词了
It's fine that there are new lines. It still separating it into the words we have.
出现新行是允许的 因为它仍在对现有引用进行分解
We still have some issues, like the parentheses is included as part of David.
当然 仍有问题存在 如在 David 项中 括号也被加进来了
So this quote wouldn't show up for the keyword David.
这样以来 以 David 作关键词进行搜索时 该引用就不会出现
I'll leave it for you to decide at the end of the class whether computing
课程结束时 我会交给各位来决定
is a business more like show business or business more like accounting.
计算机科学更像娱乐业还是会计业
I'm going with show business, though.
我个人呢 认为它更像娱乐业
So now let's see if you can write the code to build an index using the URLs collected from our Web problem.
现在 来看一下大家能否使用 从网页问题中搜集到的 URL 来写代码构建索引